Our pianist, Paula, works on the inventory team at the warehouse,
and her supervisor has asked her to list out all equipment that needs
repairs or maintenance so that she can coordinate repairs.
While Paula understands the project is necessary,
it just doesn't excite her.
She even worries she could fail,
given how little she knows about it.
But as soon as she recognizes that this is an opportunity to decrease the stress
for her and her coworkers caused by broken equipment, her motivation increases.
With a clear link to something that is personally meaningful, the well-being of her team,
the task at hand feels less daunting and more worthwhile.
So Paula sets a clear learning intention for herself:
be able to list out all equipment in need of repairs,
so that both she and her team can make an informed decision.
She sets up time to talk to her coworkers to better understand which equipment
requires repairs, and then does further research to document the results.
The more she learns about which equipment needs repairs, the more ways she sees
how this can improve her team members' lives, which in turn energizes her.
When Paula takes the pressure off herself
to offer a quick recommendation,
and recognizes she should spend time learning and exploring,
the task becomes easier and more fun.
After a few weeks, and with her team's input, she is able to develop a full list
of equipment and help her supervisor submit a complete repair order.
The research is clear that performing in the long run requires you to release
performance goals in the early stages, in order to focus on your learning.
And the research is clear about something else, too:
that the best learning intentions
are the ones that are linked to meaning.
When we have to learn something difficult,
and over a longer period of time,
it's critical to be intrinsically motivated.
Think about the last time you engaged in an activity
that you truly enjoyed and that was personally rewarding.
There was no prize, threat, or external factor
influencing your behavior,
only this heartwarming feeling inside of you.
That's intrinsic motivation.
It makes us feel more empowered
and in charge of our experience,
because it touches on our deep human need for autonomy:
to choose where we focus our energy.
Being able to see the task at hand as connected to something
important to you is a powerfully different way to learn.
In Paula's case, her ability to make an explicit connection between doing a good job
of creating the equipment repair list and realizing it would improve things for her team
motivated her brain to focus and engage deeply
in the activities involved.
In turn, this makes learning easier, and you are
more likely to successfully achieve your intention.